<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>strings on Robert Schnitman</title>
    <link>https://robertschnitman.netlify.com/tags/strings/</link>
    <description>Recent content in strings on Robert Schnitman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://robertschnitman.netlify.com/tags/strings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>BASops: Utility Functions for BASIC Dialects</title>
      <link>https://robertschnitman.netlify.com/2022/10/21/basops/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robertschnitman.netlify.com/2022/10/21/basops/</guid>
      <description>While I primarily have been focusing on my current employment and freelance projects, I also have made incremental changes to existing packages/repos on my GitHub. In particular, I have merged my VBAOps and LOBOps repos, as the latter is a translation of the former. As such, I have a new repo called BASops, which serves as the primary repo where I will write and maintain utility functions for dialects of BASIC, such as VBA and LibreOffice Basic (LO Basic).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Package: stringops, String-Processing Tools and Synonyms for R</title>
      <link>https://robertschnitman.netlify.com/2020/08/08/new-package-stringops/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robertschnitman.netlify.com/2020/08/08/new-package-stringops/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionWhen creating syntax, one has to ask themselves about the naming scheme: should I make the functions short for typing efficiency, or long for increased readability? Ruby has the former benefit, but sometimes the methods can be difficult to remember (e.g. is it len or length? Is it swapcase or swap_case?), as there isn’t a consistent naming scheme–however, some functions have synonyms to help those from other programming languages learn Ruby faster (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vectorized String Functions in AutoIt</title>
      <link>https://robertschnitman.netlify.com/2020/06/20/vectorized-string-functions-in-autoit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robertschnitman.netlify.com/2020/06/20/vectorized-string-functions-in-autoit/</guid>
      <description>1. IntroductionIn my current workplace at Leverage Retirement, Inc., I use Autoit to automate file management operations, such as copying files to archive directories and checking whether files exist for the morning processes. These operations involve the application of regular expressions to find out whether specific files match a given pattern (e.g. Deposit \d{4}-\d{2}-\d{2}, where \d{x} represents a number of x digits). While there are many string functions in AutoIt, most of them apply only to constants and not arrays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vectorized String Methods in Ruby</title>
      <link>https://robertschnitman.netlify.com/2020/06/19/vectorized-string-methods-in-ruby/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robertschnitman.netlify.com/2020/06/19/vectorized-string-methods-in-ruby/</guid>
      <description>1. IntroductionI have been dabbling with the Ruby programming language for work purposes lately. Overall, I enjoy its concise, fun syntax and string methods such as .chomp to remove new-line characters–and I especially like the compactness of map. However, I believe that I have been too accustomed to R’s default property of functions being vectorized, as I initially had some trouble with handling arrays and employing string methods.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>